Symianakis Sifis

Mafsolou 67, Heraklion, Crete, p.c.: 71 601 sifis.symianakis@gmail.com

Birth: September 1986. Heraklion City, Crete

Telephone: +30 6946 006 437



Resume

I am a backend software engineer working with state-of-the-art technologies and love to participate in high level designs, software implementations and best practice methodologies. I have studied Computer Science Department at University of Crete and completed master studies on ubiquitous computing at Hellenic Open University. My master thesis is based on ubiquitous systems, researching on simplifying editing and summarization video process using context. I am a father of two lovely kids and my long-term expectation is to become a solution architect. For a detailed portfolio including my published projects and applications please contact me via email.

Education

2013 - 2016 Master on Ubiquitous and Mobile Computing MSc

Hellenic Open University

Mobile Computing, Mobility, Spherical computing, Ubiquitous Environments, Ontologies, HCI of ubiquitous systems, Internet of Things, Mobile Wireless Networks.

2004 - 2009 Bachelor on Computer Science Department

University of Crete, Heraklion

Software Development, Object Oriented Programming, Design and development of information systems (UML), Advanced Programming, Network Concepts, Computer Scienc, Data structures, Hardware Design, Computer Organization, Compilers.

Experience

09/2018 - Today

Pancreta Bank

- Software Engineering (9/2018 Present)
 - Drive software solution regarding PSD2 Open Banking Regulation with compliance of Berlin Group Standard
 - Open Banking API Management: Develop and manage API products with IBM API Connect tool.
 - Software Architecture: Design software components that are part of the customer open banking journey
 - Strong Customer Authentication
 - Open Banking Consent Management
 - Customer support: Registration, subscription and documentation through Developer's Portal
 - o Tester: Customer journey in a holistic approach
 - Design and develop bank's middleware layer in a micro services architecture in order to support system-to-system integrations.

- Software Architecture: Structure micro services based on the Spring Cloud of Netflix and design system-to-system integrations.
 - Cloud features: Service discovery, Client-side load balancer, Internal and external routing through proxy
 - o Infrastructure features: Oauth2 authentication service, Configuration server with git integration, io-logger
 - o Integrations: Government, E-banking Vendor, Core-banking vendor, PSD2 vendor

<u>Tech Stack</u>: Spring cloud Netflix (https://spring.io/projects/spring-cloud-netflix)

- Back-End Development: Develop loosely coupled micro services with concrete business capabilities.
 - o Business oriented rest services (E.g. cards, direct-debits, customers)
 - PSD2 open banking rest services (E.g. accounts, payments, consents)
 - Wrapping integration services (E.g. Core-banking soap API, e-banking rest API)
 - o Soap Web Services: as a middleware for AADE communication
 - o Unit & integration tests for delivered software

Tech Stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Junit, Postgres, Oracle

07/2014 -8/2018

Cyberlogic (e-Tourism Solutions).

- **Lead Software Developer** (8/2016-8/2018)
 - Lead development team: backend and frontend integration
 - Follow agile methodology: scrum, 2-week sprints
- Full Stack Software Engineer (8/2015-7/2016)
 - Back-End Development: REST APIs developed with .NET, use of MSSQL relational and MongoDB document-based database
 - Follow Domain Drive Design
 - Unit Testing

Tech Stack: C#, Domain Driven Design, MSSQL, MongoDB

- > Frontend Engineer (7/2014-7-2015)
 - Front-End Development: Web applications with Angular framework (AngularJS and Angular. Unit test with Jasmine.

Tech Stack: Angular JS, Angular (2-4), Typescript, Bootstrap, HTML5, Jasmine Testing

Mobile Development: Native android applications

Tech Stack: Android framework, Java 7

12/2012 - 05/2013

Front-End Developer @ Municipality of Gortys

 Front-end development: Operational Site of Municipality Tech Stack: HTML, CSS

05/2011 - 05/2012

Information Technology Support @ Ministry of Health (Heraklion).

IT Support of information systems, issuing with financial and administration information systems.

10/2008 -10/2009 **Technology Sales Representative** @ OTE (Telecommunications)

Making sales of telecommunication and internet based services and equipment including after sales support.

Courses

2019 (3 days)	Voxxed Days Athens 2019: International series events focusing on software engineer technologies and tech trends.
2016 (3 days)	Droidcon Thessaloniki Conference in android framework and mobile development. Talking about new technologies and networking. #Droidcon
2016 (3 days)	Agile Unconference #AgileCrete Coach+Dev Camp 2016.
2015 (3 days)	Agile Unconference #AgileCrete Coach+Dev Camp 2015. Agile Software Development. Collaboration. Tools. Estimating. Continuous improvements. Flexibility on customers changing minds. Agile Principles.
2011 (1 week)	Designing Web Application with Open Source Tools. #Training Institute of the National Center School of Public Administration and Local Government (EKDDA).
2011 (1 week)	E-Government and Citizens. Training. #Institute of the National Center School of Public Administration and Local Government (EKDDA).

Additional Info

Military Duties Fulfilled

Interests Software Engineering, S/E Courses, Developer Community, Books, Gaming, Sports

LinkedIn Web Page https://www.linkedin.com/in/sifis-symianakis/